# **Tomasz Stanisz**

Senior GL Analyst



# **Summary**

I've been working in Finance and Accounting departments for more than 8 years in different companies. Experience that I have gained was preceded by 5 years studies in field of Finance and Accounting. I started from small accounting office as junior through corporated AR, regular GL analyst and currently Senior GL Analyst with specialization for Global Process review, month ends cooperation with offshore and improvements in these areas



# 8

# Personal Info

#### **Address**

Aleja Wyścigowa 14a 02-681 Warszawa

#### Phone

+43 725-214-022

#### **Email**

fremen1990@gmail.com

### Date of birth

1990-10-31

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomaszstanisz-85818683/



# Work History

2020-01

- present

## Senior GL Analyst

Marsh & McLennan Companies, Warszawa, Polska

- Review balance sheet reconciliations, implement improvements and solve differences
- Perform quality checks on work performed by the offshore teams,
- Review, approve and prepare requests for ad hoc analysis of various types of financial information utilizing operational and financial analytics as appropriate for the situation,
- Ensure all month-end, quarterly and yearly tasks deliverables are met,
- Assist with auditors and audit requirements,
- Support journal entry process and month end reporting,
- Cooperation with India Hub on daily basis,
- Implementation improvements, automations and VBA support.

## 2019-03

- 2020-01

## **Regional Accounting Analyst**

AkzoNobel

- Supported in an accurate and timely way the monthly, quarterly, hardclose and year-end financial closing for entities in the region,
- Supported consolidation of legal entity statements and local statutory reporting in the region,
- Reviewed P&L and BS from an accounting perspective in SAP/HFM,
- Managed A-forms (Hyperion Financial Managment),
- Identified and escalated issues for further process improvement,
- Drove standardization and quality in balance sheet reconciliation process,

#### 2017-01

- 2019-02

## **GL Accountant Operation Analyst**

Accenture

• Managed month-end, quarter-end and year-end closings,



# Skills

Accounting

Financial Reporti

Financial Reporting

Improvements & Automations

**Taxation** 

Quick learner









## Software

Microsoft Excel

SAP

Oracle

\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*

VBA

▲.

HTML + CSS

JavaScript

\*\*\*\*

I hereby give consent for my personal data to be processed by **SmartWays** for the purpose of conducting recruitment for the position for which I am applying.

- Quarterly balance sheet and P & L Fluctuation Analysis,
- Analyzed monthly and quarterly PnL cost movements and variances,
- Managed Fixed Assets,
- Managed balance sheet accounts reconciliations,
- Prepared of VAT, PIT and CIT declarations.

**O2C Credit Managment Specialist** 

# 2014-11

- 2016-12

Tate & Lyle

- Gathered, analyzed and interpreted financial information,
- Created credit limits and payment terms,
- Generated timely standard reports for regions US, EMEA and APAC,
- Managed disputes and drove to resolution,
- Managed credit hold accounts by reviewing held orders and analyzed customers.

## 2013-01 - 2014-08

Accountant

Agroma Kielce Sp. z o.o.

- Maintained accounting records,
- Kept HR and payroll,
- Prepared declarations VAT, CIT, PIT, ZUS,
- Prepared of interim analyzes,
- Suppoerted audit and external controls.



# **Education**

2009-10 - 2014-07 Uniwersytet Łódzki, Finance and accounting, Master's degree

### 2014-01

- present

ACCA F1-F5

ACCA (Association of Chartered Certified Accountants) F1 to F5 passed - student status



**Projects** 

- present

**Process Council** 



Volunteering

2020-03

- present

ANON - Animals Nature Organization Non-Profit
Web Developer



Polish ★★★★

English ★★★★

Russian \*\*\*



Hobby

Motorcycles

Sport (BJJ, strenght training and running)

Music (drummer and guitarist)